<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE terms SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/writerside/1.0/glossary.dtd">
<terms>
<term name="Snapshot">A point-in-time copy of selected files/folders stored in a repository.</term>
    <term name="Repository">Storage location that contains backup snapshots and metadata.</term>
    <term name="Retention Policy">Rules governing how long snapshots are kept before pruning.</term>
    <term name="Pattern Group">A set of glob patterns defining inclusion/exclusion rules.</term>
    <term name="Restic">Open-source backup program used as underlying engine.</term>
    <term name="MTBF">Mean Time Between Failures.</term>
    <term name="Encryption">The process of converting data into a form that can only be read by authorized parties.</term>
    <term name="Backup Schedule">A predefined routine specifying when and how backups are automatically created.</term>
    <term name="Pruning">The process of deleting old or unnecessary backup snapshots based on the retention policy.</term>
    <term name="Metadata">Data that describes other data, such as information about snapshots, file versions, and structure.</term>
    <term name="Incremental">Referring to a process that builds upon previous steps or states, adding only what has changed since the last operation.</term>
    <term name="Incremental Backup">A backup that includes only the changes made since the last backup, reducing size and time.</term>
    <term name="Glob Patterns">Text patterns used to match file or folder names, often in inclusion/exclusion rules.</term>
    <term name="CLI">Command-Line Interface used to interact with software via text-based commands.</term>
    <term name="Bare-Metal Recovery">The process of restoring a complete system (operating system, files, etc.) after a critical failure.</term>
    <term name="Audit Log">A record of events and system activities for tracking and verifying actions.</term>
    <term name="Audit Logs">A collection of records documenting system events and activities for security monitoring and compliance verification.</term>
    <term name="Disaster Recovery">A process aimed at restoring system functionality after significant data loss or corruption.</term>
    <term name="Integrity Check">A method of ensuring consistency and correctness, often performed using `restic check`.</term>
    <term name="Retention Pruning">The deletion of older snapshots based on rules defined in a retention policy.</term>
    <term name="GDPR">General Data Protection Regulation that governs personal data protection and privacy in the EU.</term>
    <term name="OWASP-ASVS">Open Web Application Security Project's Application Security Verification Standard.</term>
    <term name="Audit Verify">A process by which the integrity and tamper resistance of backup audit logs are confirmed.</term>
    <term name="SRS">Software Requirements Specification document outlining project scope and requirements.</term>
    <term name="UX/UI">User Experience and User Interface design aspects of software.</term>
    <term name="Power Users">Highly technical users who utilize advanced features of the application.</term>
    <term name="Everyday Users">Typical users who interact with the application for standard day-to-day functions.</term>
    <term name="TimeLocker">The name of the product being developed, a user-friendly backup application.</term>
    <term name="S3">Amazon Simple Storage Service, a cloud storage platform.</term>
    <term name="SMB">Server Message Block, a network file sharing protocol.</term>
    <term name="NFS">Network File System, a distributed file system protocol.</term>
    <term name="SFTP">SSH File Transfer Protocol, a secure file transfer protocol.</term>
    <term name="B2">Backblaze B2 Cloud Storage, a cloud storage service.</term>
    <term name="cron/systemd">Scheduling mechanisms in Linux used for automated tasks.</term>
    <term name="point-in-time restores">A recovery feature allowing restoration to a specific moment in time.</term>
    <term name="In Transit">Data that is being transmitted between systems.</term>
    <term name="At Rest">Data that is stored and not actively being used.</term>
    <term name="Bandwidth Throttling">Limiting network bandwidth usage to control resource consumption.</term>
    <term name="JSON-RPC">A remote procedure call protocol encoded in JSON.</term>
    <term name="REST API">Representational State Transfer Application Programming Interface.</term>
    <term name="ASVS">Application Security Verification Standard.</term>
    <term name="CI/CD">Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment, automated software development practices.</term>
    <term name="HSTS">HTTP Strict Transport Security, a web security policy mechanism.</term>
    <term name="AES-256">Advanced Encryption Standard with 256-bit key, a strong encryption algorithm.</term>
    <term name="CAPTCHA">Completely Automated Public Turing test to tell Computers and Humans Apart.</term>
    <term name="ISO/IEC 29148">A standard for requirements engineering in systems and software.</term>
    <term name="WCAG 2.2 AA">Web Content Accessibility Guidelines version 2.2, AA compliance level.</term>
    <term name="FR/NFR">Functional Requirements/Non-Functional Requirements.</term>
    <term name="Auditing">The systematic recording and examination of system activities to ensure compliance and security.</term>
    <term name="Repository Management">The process of creating, configuring, and maintaining backup storage locations.</term>
    <term name="Backup Operations">Activities related to creating, scheduling, and verifying backups.</term>
    <term name="Policy Management">The administration of rules governing backup retention, scheduling, and security.</term>
    <term name="Retention">The period of time for which backups are kept before being deleted.</term>
    <term name="Verification">The process of confirming that backups are complete, accurate, and restorable.</term>
    <term name="Integrity">The assurance that data has not been altered or corrupted during storage or transmission.</term>
    <term name="Prune">To remove outdated or unnecessary backup snapshots according to retention policies.</term>
    <term name="Audit Trails">Chronological records of system activities that provide documentary evidence of operations.</term>
    <term name="Users">Individuals who interact with the application, including everyday users and power users.</term>
    <term name="User-friendly Design">An approach to software design that prioritizes ease of use and intuitive interfaces.</term>
    <term name="Command-line Tools">Software utilities operated via text-based interfaces rather than graphical user interfaces.</term>
    <term name="Scheduling Backups">The process of configuring automated backups to run at predetermined times.</term>
    <term name="Scheduled Backups">Backups that are automatically executed according to a predefined schedule.</term>
    <term name="Auditability">The quality of a system that allows its operations to be independently examined and verified.</term>
    <term name="Repositories">Multiple storage locations that contain backup snapshots and metadata.</term>
    <term name="Security">Measures taken to protect data from unauthorized access, corruption, or theft.</term>
    <term name="Usability">The ease with which users can learn and use a software application to achieve their goals.</term>
    <term name="Policy Enforcement">The automated application and monitoring of backup policies to ensure compliance with defined rules.</term></terms>
