<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE terms SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/writerside/1.0/glossary.dtd">
<terms>
    <term name="SDLC">Software Development Life Cycle - the process used to design, develop, and test high-quality software.</term>
    <term name="AI Assistance">The use of artificial intelligence tools like large language models to help with software development tasks.</term>
    <term name="LLM">Large Language Model - an AI system trained on vast amounts of text data that can generate human-like text and assist in various tasks.</term>
    <term name="Junie">The AI assistant used in this project to help with development tasks.</term>
    <term name="Solo Developer">A developer working independently on a software project without a team.</term>
    <term name="Requirements Definition">The phase of identifying and documenting what the software should do.</term>
    <term name="Design">The phase of planning how the software will be structured and function.</term>
    <term name="Implementation">The phase where the actual code is written according to the design specifications.</term>
    <term name="Testing">The process of evaluating a system to identify any gaps, errors, or missing requirements.</term>
    <term name="Deployment">The process of releasing the software to the production environment.</term>
    <term name="Maintenance">The process of modifying and updating software after deployment to correct faults and improve performance.</term>
    <term name="SRS">Software Requirements Specification - a document that describes the requirements for a software system.</term>
    <term name="Simplified SRS">A streamlined version of a Software Requirements Specification designed for solo developers.</term>
    <term name="UX">User Experience - the overall experience of a person using a product, especially in terms of how easy or pleasing it is to use.</term>
    <term name="UI">User Interface - the means by which users interact with a software application.</term>
    <term name="Simplified UX/UI Design">A streamlined approach to user experience and interface design for solo developers.</term>
    <term name="AI Prompts">Specific questions or instructions given to an AI assistant to get helpful responses for development tasks.</term>
    <term name="MoSCoW Method">A prioritization technique used in requirements management (Must have, Should have, Could have, Won't have).</term>
    <term name="Iterative Development">A development approach where the software is built incrementally, with each iteration adding functionality.</term>
    <term name="Automated Testing">The use of software tools to execute tests automatically and compare actual outcomes with expected outcomes.</term>
    <term name="Manual Testing">The process of manually testing software for defects without the use of automation tools.</term>
    <term name="Risk-based Testing">A testing approach that prioritizes testing efforts based on the risk of failure and impact of features.</term>
    <term name="Continuous Integration">The practice of merging all developer working copies to a shared mainline several times a day.</term>
    <term name="Version Control">A system that records changes to a file or set of files over time so that specific versions can be recalled later.</term>
    <term name="Git">A distributed version control system for tracking changes in source code during software development.</term>
    <term name="GitHub">A platform and cloud-based service for software development and version control using Git.</term>
    <term name="Code Review">A systematic examination of computer source code intended to find and fix mistakes.</term>
    <term name="Technical Debt">The implied cost of additional rework caused by choosing an easy solution now instead of using a better approach that would take longer.</term>
    <term name="Refactoring">The process of restructuring existing computer code without changing its external behavior.</term>
    <term name="Documentation">Written text or illustrations that accompany software to explain how it works or how to use it.</term>
    <term name="README">A file that contains information about other files in a directory or archive, typically providing basic information about the software.</term>
</terms>